# Daniel A. Pinedo

# Strategy Management & People Operations

**4** 213,999,5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

# **SUMMARY**

Manager specialized in business strategy and people operations. Experience in creating selection tools that incorporate machine-assisted decision-making. Leader that elicits focus, deep listening, and insights in colleague interactions. Extensive background in research, evaluation, and statistical methods.

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

### **Associate Consultant**

### **Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab**

## 03/2019 - Current

Ownership of project deliverables and translation of research into business case.

- · PROJECT 4: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into secondary stage with global alignment teams
- PROJECT 5: SME for values-fit and values-signaling interview design prototype
- PROJECT 6: SME for bias reduction and increased inclusion selection assessment design prototype

# Research Associate

# **Accenture PLC, Talent Innovation Lab**

## 11/2018 - Promotion

Organizational behavior & evaluation research specialist.

- PROJECT 1: Literature review for behavioral interview theory
- PROJECT 2: SME for behavioral interview theory; initiated implementation plan with global management team
- · PROJECT 3: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into pilot stage with global alignment teams

# **Executive Coach**

#### **Getty Leadership Institute / LeAD Labs**

**1** 05/2019 - 08/2019

% https://gli.cgu.edu/

Primary support for three senior international museum executives during leadership training and assessment center program

- · Assisted clients in creation of development plan based on assessment center, 360°, and StrengthsFinder results
- · Provided additional support in assessment center by scoring and acting in "troubled follower" role play scenario

# **External Consultant**

# **Undisclosed Property Management Firm**

**1** 03/2019 - 06/2019

Organizational culture consult for private, family-owned property management firm currently undergoing succession-related change with a portfolio of over \$1 billion in residential and commercial real-estate assets.

- · Diagnosed internal-facing stress related to values signaling from family management through executive management
- Provided business case for implementing values communications strategies with potential for increased organizational commitment and overall firm performance
- · Connected overall business strategy with identified cultural values for implementation in management training

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

# Team Lead

#### **BCG Gamma Datathon**

Invite-only case competition for BCG data analytics group among graduate students from USC Marshall, UCLA Anderson, and CGU Drucker management schools.

- Recruited ad-hoc cross-functional team of experts in the fields of artificial intelligence, financial engineering, data science, management, and organizational behavior.
- · Provided case formulation training, strategy, and high-level technical architecture for technical solution.

# **External Consultant**

#### **ICM Partners**

**1** 09/2018 - 01/2019

% icmpartners.com

Organizational behavior project for Top 5 creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring.

• 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new hire.

# **EDUCATION**

# MA Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

#### **Claremont Graduate University**

• Emphasis in Business Administration

# MA Clinical Psychology

### **Sofia University**

Palo Alto, CA

# BA

### **Naropa University**

# **SKILLS**

# **Programming**

R C++ Python LaTeX Java

### **Statistics**

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis Factor Analysis Structural Equation Modeling